博士 博士 小心
Doctor! Doctor, look out!
他去哪了 看见他了吗
Where's he gone? Do you see him?
他在那 停下 不
There he is. Stop! No!
小心
Watch out!
在那儿 那儿
There! There!
它就是这样吼叫起来
That's what it did, it went...
如果你认为那是我人生中最刺激的一天
And if you think that was the most exciting day of my life,
等听完其余的再说吧
wait till you hear the rest.
噢 天哪
Oh, boy.
我就在那 和那个吼叫的东西一起
So there I was, with that thing going...
过来 好孩子 吃东西 过来
Here, boy. Eat the food. Come on.
看看这可爱的食物 是不是很棒 非常棒
Look at the lovely food, isn't that nice? Isn't it? Yes, it is!
离开这里 快点
Get out of here, quickly.
真乖 谁想吃猪排骨
That's a boy! Who'd like a porky choppy, then?
我说"跑"
I said run!
错了 你真是越帮越忙
Wrong one! You made it worse!
你说"蓝的"
You said blue.
我说"不要蓝的"
I said not blue!
坚持住
Hold on.
等等
我见过你吗
Don't I know you?
你根本无法想像 博士的机器
You can't imagine it, the Doctor's machine.
世界上最美妙的声音
The most beautiful sound in the world.
这不是我第一次见到博士
That wasn't the first time I met the Doctor
当然也不是最后一次
and it certainly wasn't the last.
噢 不
Oh, no.
因为这是个很棒的开场 我才放在开头
I just put that bit at the beginning because it's a brilliant opening.
这是一个关于我
But this is the story of me
和我与外星人相遇的故事
and my encounters with alien life forms.
事先警告一下
But be warned!
因为它会越来越恐怖
Because it is gonna get scary.
我可能需要一个遥控
I need a remote control zoom.
现在我只能身体前倾来操作 恐…怖
I'm having to do that with a lean, the scary.
但不用担心
But don't worry
因为不会只有我坐在这儿讲话 哦不
'cause it's not just me sitting here talking. Oh, no.
拿着相机的是厄什拉
That's Ursula on camera.
你好
Hello.
我的好朋友 厄什拉·布雷克
My good friend Ursula Blake
拿着我全新的摄像机
on my brand-new camera.
那里以前是我家 就在那儿
That was my family home, down there.
我尽力了 但现在有两个女人住着
I did try but there's two women live there now.
她们不太友好
They're a bit severe.
算了吧
So, never mind.
但那是一切开始的地方
But that is where it all started
因为那是我第一次见到博士
'cause that's when I first met the Doctor.
让我想想 我应该是三四岁大
What was it? I must've been three or four years old.
午夜 我走下楼
Middle of the night I went downstairs,
这个男人就站在那
and there was this man.
发生了什么
So what happened?
埃尔顿 告诉我 他为什么会在那里
Elton? Tell me, why was he there?
我不知道
I don't know.
我到现在都不知道
I still don't know.
那是好多年前的事了
All those years ago.
好了 先说要事
Okay, first things first.
我叫埃尔顿 不要和某位歌手弄混了
My name is Elton, not to be confused with...
我离开学校 找了份工作
I left school, I got a job,
在瑞塔后勤公司当运输经理
transport manager at Rita Logistics,
普通小运输公司
modest little haulage company,
十分普通的生活 然后…
perfectly normal life, and then...
一切都变得疯狂
it all went mad!
两年前 我在镇上
Two years ago I was in town,
我正在备货 没什么特别的 都是些普通东西
I was stocking up, you know, nothing special, all the usual stuff.
突然
When all of a sudden...
商店窗口里的假人
Shop-window dummies
竟然活了
come to life.
我活下来了 显然
I survived, obviously.
十二个月之后 我重回小镇
Twelve months later, I'm back in town.
想买套新衣服 好好买件像样的
I'm up West looking for a new suit,something nice and smart,
这时突然有一架飞行器从头顶飞过
when I hear this plane overhead...
但这还没完
But it wasn't over yet.
因为之后 圣诞节
'Cause then, Christmas Day.
我在床上熟睡 甜美而安逸 早上七点多
I'm in bed, fast asleep, nice and cosy,7:45 in the morning,
突然之间…
when all of a sudden...
我被困在床上
And I'm stuck in bed, all right,
因为地上到处是玻璃碎片
'cause there's glass everywhere,
而我光着脚
and I was barefoot.
我得制作一个简陋的的滑轮系统
I had to invent this rudimentary pulley system
好把我的鞋子吊上来 当我弄完时…
just to reach my boots, and by the time I'd done that...
那就是一切的开始
And that's when it all started happening.
我就是这么认识厄什拉的
That's how I met Ursula.
他叫博士
His name is the Doctor.
也这样认识了维克多·肯尼迪
That's how I met Victor Kennedy.
你这个蠢货
You stupid man!
还这么认识了杰琪·泰勒
That's how I met Jackie Tyler.
姓埃尔顿的人可不常见
You don't meet many Eltons.
也是因为这样 我终于见到了博士
And that's how I finally met the Doctor.
并发现了真相
And realised the truth.
我得说
I should say
这不是我生活的全部
this isn't, you know, my whole life.
并非都是太空船之类的东西
It's not all spaceships and stuff.
因为我喜欢很多东西
'Cause I'm into all sorts of things.
我喜欢足球
I like football.
喜欢喝酒 喜欢西班牙
I like a drink. I like Spain.
如果要说一样我真的非常爱的
And if there's one thing I really, really love,
那就是杰夫·林恩和电光乐队
then it's Jeff Lynne and the Electric Light Orchestra.
因为你根本抵挡不住他们的魅力
'Cause you can't beat a bit of ELO.
♪ The sun is shining in the sky ♪
♪ There ain't a cloud in sight ♪
♪ It's stopped raining ♪
♪ Everybody's in the play ♪
♪ And don't you know it's a beautiful day ♪
♪ Hey hey hey… ♪
所以
So,
巨大的太空船漂浮在伦敦上空
great big spaceship hanging over London,
想像一下吧
imagine the theories.
因特网彻底崩溃
The internet went into meltdown.
但我继续深挖
But I kept on digging.
有事情还在发生
Something was going on.
是的
Oh, yes.
某天在某个不起眼的博客里
And then one day, on some obscure little blog
博主叫厄什拉·布雷克
by someone called Ursula Blake.
那是怎样的几率
It was, like, chance in a million.
是他 又是那个男人
It was him, it was that man again.
但照片是新的 在圣诞节拍的
But the photo was new. It was taken on Christmas Day,
但圣诞节刚刚过去
but Christmas just gone,
而他看起来还和原来一样
and he looked exactly the same.
他叫博士
His name is the Doctor.
什么博士
Doctor what?
人们都只知道这一点
That's all anyone knows.
在圣诞节那天 我在外面到处拍照
At Christmas Day, I was taking photos all over the place.
我都快被那些事情搞疯了
I went mad with it all,
太空船 激光等等一切事情
spaceships and lasers and everything.
我们那晚都去了特拉法加广场
We all went to Trafalgar Square that night
因为每个人都在欢庆自己能活下来
'cause everyone was celebrating just being alive,
我在他经过时拍了照片
and I snapped him in passing, that's all.
就是一个普通男子
He was just some bloke.
我当时没意识到他很重要
I didn't realise he was significant
直到后来斯金纳先生告诉了我
until Mr Skinner pointed it out.
谁是斯金纳先生
Who's Mr Skinner?
噢 是我们一群人
Oh, there's a few of us.
秘密圣所 都在研究这个博士
The inner sanctum. All studying this Doctor.
我见过他 博士 我发誓
I've seen him, the Doctor, I swear to you.
我小时候见过他
I saw him when I was a kid.
他在我家里 就在楼下
He was in my house and he was downstairs.
别告诉我他看起来和现在一模一样
Don't tell me, he looked exactly the same then as he does now.
是的
Yes.
噢 老天 你相信我
Oh, my God, you believe me.
这就是我怎么认识厄什拉的 多亏了博士
So that's how I met Ursula. All thanks to the Doctor.
结果发现我们都看了相同的网站
Turns out we read all the same sites
而且她离我住的地方只有半英里路
and she only lived half a mile away.
她是一个很好的伙伴 可怜的厄什拉
She was like a proper mate. Poor Ursula.
但如她所说
But like she said,
这是一个小团体
there was this little community,
人数很少
the select few,
他们的故事都和博士有关
all with their stories of the Doctor.
这个小群体经常碰面
This little gang used to meet up
通常在麦考提街的老图书馆下面
underneath the old library on Maccateer Street.
斯金纳先生姓科林 但我们总叫他斯金纳先生
Mr Skinner, first name Colin, but we always called him Mr Skinner.
不知道为什么 只是这样叫
I don't know why, we just did.
对我而言 博士不是一个人
...to me, the Doctor isn't a man,
他更是一个原型的集合
he's more a collection of archetypes.
然后是布里吉
Then there was Bridget.
这些不同的博士来来去去
...all these different Doctors come and go,
但唯一的不变的特征是这个假的警亭
but the single constant factor is this faux police box.
它突然出现 贯穿所有的故事
It keeps cropping up throughout history.
她住在北边
She lived way up north,
但是她从大老远赶过来 从不错过会议
but she travelled down without fail just for the meetings.
接下来是布丽斯
Then there was Bliss.
我要做的是
What I'm trying to do
总结博士对我们来说意味着什么
is sum up the Doctor. What he means to us.
她曾经多么甜美 布丽斯
She was ever so sweet, Bliss.
"保佑布丽斯" 我们经常这样说
Bless Bliss, we used to say.
他能够象征什么 以及他应该象征什么
What he could represent and what he should represent
还有他
and what he
永远不会象征的某种事情
never won't represent sort of thing.
我们应该起个名字
We should have a name.
你知道 作为一个小组
You know, as a group.
名字是很重要的
Names are very important.
我们需要的是一个强有力的名字
What we need is a good, strong name,
像一个团队 比如…
like a team. Something like...
伦敦调查和侦探事务所
London Investigation 'N' Detective Agency.
简称LINDA
LINDA for short.
你再说一次
Say it again?
伦敦调查和侦探事务所
London Investigation 'N' Detective Agency.
怎么是"N"
"N"?
鱼 & 薯条
Fish 'n' chips.
摇 & 滚
Rock 'n' roll.
恰克·迪莫斯 & 布莱尔
Chaka Demus 'n' Pliers.
LINDA 我喜欢 它不会太严肃
Ah! LINDA, I like it. It's not too solemn.
我喜欢"N"
I like the 'N'.
我们是LINDA的男人  - 还有女人
We're the men from LINDA. And the women.
LINDA 联合组织
LINDA united.
你当场想到的吗
Did you think of that on the spot?
不 我早就想用这个了
No, I've wanted to use it for years.
敬一杯LINDA
I give you LINDA.
LINDA
LINDA!
所以我们每周都见面
So we'd all meet up every week
我们会谈点博士的东西
and we'd talk about the Doctor for a bit.
不久后 布里吉开始弄吃的
But after a while, Bridget started cooking.
哦 天哪 真是太棒了
Oh, my God, that's gorgeous!
不 真的
No, really. Wow.
其余的人 缩手
The rest of you, get your hands off!
接下来斯金纳先生会开始读书
Next thing you know, Mr Skinner started his readings,
因为他自己撰写小说
'cause he was writing his own novel.
这是最后一次你坐魔鬼列车
"That's the last time you ride the Ghost Train,
琼尼·弗兰斯塔 现在祈祷吧
johnny Franzetta. "Now say your prayers!"
待续
To be continued.
不
No!
随着时间流逝 我们越来越了解对方
Time went on. We got to know each other better and better.
在我女儿失踪后 我开始加入这个组织
I only started all this because my daughter disappeared.
但不是外星人把她带走
But it wasn't aliens that took her away.
而是毒品
It was just drugs.
我每周都来伦敦 为了找她
I come down to London every week and I just keep looking for her.
噢 布里吉
Oh, Bridget.
♪ I gave my love a chicken ♪
♪ It had no bone ♪
♪ I gave my love a cherry ♪
♪ It had no stone… ♪
♪ I've got a brand new pair of roller-skates ♪
♪ You've got a brand-new key… ♪
后来发现布里吉竟然会弹钢琴
Then it turned out that Bridget could play the piano,
我也说出了我对电光乐队的爱好
and I confessed my love of ELO.
接下来你也能猜到 LINDA乐队
Next thing you know, musical LINDA.
♪ You got me running going out of my mind ♪
♪ You got me thinking that I'm wasting my time ♪
♪ Don't bring me down… ♪
只是好玩而已
just for fun.
♪ Don't bring me down…♪
该你了
Your go.
哦 不
Oh, no.
该你了
You go.
小心 别被电线绊倒了
Now, careful. Mind the cables
然后一切都改变了
And that's when it all changed.
在三月的一个周二晚上
That Tuesday night in March.
他来了
That's when he arrived.
亮灯
Lights.
那天我们遇见了维克多·肯尼迪
That's when we met Victor Kennedy.
我们的黄金时代 结束了
And the golden age was gone.
我们终于见面了
So, we meet at last,
LINDA
LINDA.
很高兴见到你 先生
Pleased to meet you, sir.
对不起 音乐太大声了吗
I'm sorry, was the music too loud?
不不不 我不握手
No, no, no. I don't shake hands.
后退后退 我饱受皮肤病折磨
Back, back. I suffer from a skin complaint.
翅疹  - 噢 你是说湿疹
Eczeema. Oh, you mean eczema.
这更糟 非常糟 我被碰到就会有水疱
Oh, this is worse, much worse. I blister to the touch.
退后退后 你们都离远点 远点
Back, back, all of you, further, further.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起 别介意我问问 你是谁
Sorry, don't mind me asking, but who are you?
我们你们的救星
I am your salvation.
那就是博士
That's the Doctor.
真的是他
That's really him.
你们忘了最初的目的
Forgotten your purpose in life.
你们沉醉于乐队 蛋糕 那些乱七八糟的东西
You, with your band and your cakes and your blubbing,
而他一直还在外面
and all the while he still exists,
博士
the Doctor.
看 快看
Look at him. just look!
向后退 你们都往后退
Move back, move back, all of you.
等一会 注意这里
Hold on, wait for this bit.
图像被切断了 但声音在继续
The picture cuts out, but the sound still continues.
听吧
Listen.
听一听宇宙的声音
Listen to the sound of the universe.
那是
Oh, that's...
是什么 怎么了
What is it? What's wrong?
别管他
Leave him!
你以前听到过 对吧
You've heard it before, haven't you?
什么时候
When?
什么时候 在哪 你当时在哪
When was it? Where? Where were you?
我忘记了
I'd forgotten.
直到现在
Till now.
是那个晚上
But it was that night.
哪晚
What night?
我只是个孩子
I was just a kid.
那就是我下楼的原因
That's why I went downstairs,
它把我吵醒了
it woke me up.
那个声音
That noise.
但那是什么声音
But what is it?
那是什么意思
What does it mean?
这是他飞船的声音
That is the sound of his spaceship.
好了 开始作业
Right then, homework!
使用火炬木文件
Using the Torchwood files,
我们可以用全新视角来看这些旧数据
we're able to look at all the old databases in a completely new light.
我们可以勾画出博士更详细的轮廓
We're able to build up a more detailed profile of the Doctor.
我已经给你们每个人分配任务
I've allocated tasks to each of you.
我希望你们…小心 注意痴疹
I'd like you to... Careful, watch the eczeema.
我希望你们能完成这些目标
I would like you to complete your targets
下周这个时候我们再在这里见面
and meet back here this time next week,
离抓住博士更近一步了
one step closer to catching the Doctor.
不要只坐在这 行动起来
Well, don't just sit there! Move!
布丽斯 是布丽斯 对吗
Um, Bliss? It is Bliss, isn't it?
是的
Yea h. Yes.
请问可以和你私下聊几句吗
Could I have a word with you in private, please?
当然
Course you can, yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
再见  - 再见
Goodbye, goodbye.
最好开始工作
Better get to work.
有很多事要做
Lots to do.
我从没把它当成工作
I never thought of it as work.
虽然这是我们一直想要的
It's what we've always wanted, though.
找到博士
To find the Doctor.
对 我想是的
Yeah, I suppose.
突然 任何人都没说一句话
All of a sudden, without anyone saying so,
我们都开始为维克多·肯尼迪工作
we were working for Victor Kennedy.
但我们得承认
But we had to admit,
他是对的 他的方法精确严格
he was right. His methods were much more rigorous.
感觉我们离博士越来越近
It' felt like we were getting closer and closer to the Doctor.
肯尼迪先生
Mr Kennedy?
是
Yes.
我们想知道…
We were wondering...
布丽斯不见了 你知道她在哪吗
No sign of Bliss. Do you know where she is?
是的 她没告诉你们吗
Yes. Didn't she tell you?
她结婚了 她留了信息
She's getting married. She left a message.
不会长久的 蠢女孩
It'll never last. Stupid girl.
加油 继续工作
Come on, back to work!
但有次我们很幸运
But we did get lucky once.
一个刚到的警亭…
A police box, newly arrived.
上面说到今天才刚到伍尔维奇
It says newly arrived today. It's in Woolwich.
不要光站在那 行动 行动 走走
Well, don't just stand there! Move! Move! Go! Go!
但别太激动 接下来就是刚开始那段
But don't get excited. That's where you came in.
伍尔维奇 警亭 红水桶 蓝水桶
Woolwich, police box, red bucket, blue bucket,
笨拙的我 等等…
me so stupid, etcetera.
没用的东西
Useless!
我被吓呆了
I just froze.
你见到了他 你却呆住了 蠢货
You met him and you froze? You stupid man!
你不能打我 你不能碰我 你有皮肤病
You can't hit me 'cause you don't touch. You get a rash and an itch and everything.
我就用这个
I can use this!
你敢用那手杖打他的话 你会被我臭骂一顿
Use that cane on him and you'll get one hell of a smack off me.
然后再一顿猛踢
And then a good kick.
你明白了吗 肯尼迪先生
Is that completely understood, Mr Kennedy?
非常明白
Duly noted.
厄什拉·布雷克
Ursula Blake,
最具有反抗的可能性
most likely to fight back.
现在 我们要改变方向
Right then, we'll change tack.
我们从侧向着手
We'll approach this sideways.
如果我们想探究博士的真相
If we're to discover the truth about the Doctor,
那么我们应该找到…她
then we need to try and find her.
每当涉及到博士的伙伴
Now, when it comes to the Doctor's companion,
火炬木的档案就离奇的缺乏
the Torchwood files are strangely lacking.
证据似乎都被毁坏了
It seems the evidence has been corrupted,
某种叫"恶狼"的病毒
something called Bad Wolf virus.
至少我们有这些照片
At least we've got these photographs.
它们是第一手资料 埃尔顿
They're first-hand evidence. Elton?
绝对是伦敦口音 她来自伦敦
It was a London accent, definitely. She's from London.
那我们到街上找
So we hit the streets.
我们就去那儿 四处拍照
We get out there. We take the photograph.
某处总会有人知道她是谁
Someone's got to know who she is somewhere.
但伦敦是个很大的地方
But London's a big place.
我很清楚 我女儿就住在那地方
I should know, my own daughter's out there.
布里吉 别把这事私人化了
Bridget, don't make this personal.
我不喜欢被碰 也不喜欢多愁善感 谢谢
I don't like to be touched literally or metaphorically, thank you very much.
我没有时间了 抓紧时间 出去
I haven't got the time. Bleeding hearts, outside.
找到那女孩 去
Find me that girl! Go!
马上行动
Now! Move!
然后开始了 不可能任务
And so it began, the impossible task.
在街道上四处搜寻
To scour the mean streets.
在大首都中找一个不知名的女孩
To search a major capital city for an unknown girl.
在失去灵魂的沸腾大都市里 穷追直至抓获那副脸孔
T 0 hum' down that face in a seething metropolis of lost souls.
在百万人中寻找那个女孩
To find that one girl in ten million.
哦 那是洛斯·泰勒 就住在那边
Oh, that's Rose Tyler. She lives just down there.
巴克纳尔楼 48号
Bucknall House, number 48.
她妈妈是杰琪·泰勒
Her mother's Jackie Tyler.
一家人都很好 就有一点古怪
Nice family, bit odd.
♪ Don't you know it's a beautiful new day ♪
喂 杰琪
Oi, Jackie!
你好 亲爱的
Hello, sweetheart.
我们今晚在"旋转独轮"那儿见 好吗
I'll see you down the Spinning Wheel tonight, yeah?
酒吧竞猜 不醉不归
Pub quiz. Get them in! All right.
我已经训练过了
I'd been trained for this.
维克多·肯尼迪的课程包含
Victor Kennedy's classes covered
基本监视和间谍活动
basic surveillance and espionage.
第一步 锁定你的目标
Step one, engage your target.
找些理由和对方交谈
Find some excuse to start a conversation.
但我该怎么做呢
But how was I going to do this? How?
打扰了 我能和你换一镑零钱吗
Excuse me, luv, you couldn't give us a quid for two fifties, could you?
好的
Yeah.just...
真可爱 祝福你
Oh, lovely. Cheers.
第二步 用不惹人起疑的方式
Step two, without provoking suspicion,
获得目标的名字
get on first-name terms with the target.
对了 我叫杰琪
My name's Jackie, by the way.
埃尔顿
I'm Elton.
姓埃尔顿的人可不常见
Oh, you don't meet many Eltons, do you?
当然 除了你
Apart from the obvious.
第三步 用笑话或些幽默策略迎取对方欢心
Step three, ingratiate yourself with a joke or some humorous device.
告诉你 埃尔顿
I tell you what, Elton.
我们本来是两个陌生人
Here we are complete strangers
我却在向你展示我的内裤
and I'm flashing you my knickers.
第四步 找到某种方法使自己融入目标的家庭
Step four, find some subtle way to integrate yourself into the target's household.
告诉你 我来这因为我的洗衣机坏了
Mind you, I'm only down here 'cause my washing machine's knackered.
我想你懂修理东西 对吗
I don't suppose you're any good at fixing things, are you?
就是这了 保险丝
Here we are. It was the fuse.
机器没有问题
There's nothing wrong with the machine.
很好 都正常工作了
That's fine, all working.
埃尔顿 我可能随时需要你
Oh, Elton, I should have you on tap.
以前有个小伙子叫米奇 这类事都是他处理的
I used to have this little mate called Mickey, he did all that stuff.
现在他已经走了 保佑他
He's gone now, bless him.
如果需要我 打电话吧
Well, if you need me, give us a call.
我给你留个号码
I'll jot down my number.
你去写 我给你倒杯茶
You do that and I'll make us a cup of tea.
坐一下吧
Go on, go and sit down.
随便看电视
Put the telly on if you want.
我不能忍受这种安静
I can't bear it silent.
我这些天老是这样 喋喋不休的
It's just me these days, rattling about.
这是我女儿 但她去旅游了
There's my daughter, but she's gone travelling.
我一直保持她房间整洁
I keep her bedroom all nice and ready though,
随时准备她回来
just in case she comes back.
她的名字是
And her name is?
洛斯
Rose.
洛斯 很不错的名字
That's a nice name, Rose.
那么 她去哪旅游了
So, where is she travelling?
到处跑
All over.
她带着手机的
She's got her mobile.
我偶尔接到她的电话 但是比我想的要少
I get a call now and then. Not as often as I'd like.
尽管如此 那个年纪 谁愿意费心给家里打电话呢
Still, at that age, who can be bothered phoning home?
她和谁一起 她有同伴吗 还是…
Yeah. Who's she with? Is it mates, is it? Or...
就是些同伴
just mates, yeah.
如果是我 有你这样会泡茶的妈妈
Well, if I had you making a nice cup of tea like this,
我才不会远离开家呢
I wouldn't stray far from home.
你真可爱
You're a charmer.
再说一次
Say it again.
太好了 我真想亲你一口
Magnificent! Oh, I could kiss you!
当然了 我不能 我的痴疹
Except I can't, of course. The eczeema.
我还用手机拍了一张她的照片
I've even got a picture of her on my phone.
太棒了
That's amazing.
你按照四个步骤准确地完成了任务
You've achieved steps one to four in precise order.
你怎么做到的
How did you manage it?
真的不容易 她把所有秘密都紧锁于胸
I had to work very hard. She keeps everything very close to her chest.
真是个好胸
That's a hell of a chest.
那么你怎继续
But how do you move on?
第五步 那才是重点问题
Step five, that's the problem.
第五步 这是这周的功课
Step five. That's this week's homework.
每个人给我一份详尽的作战计划
I want a full plan of attack from each of you.
现在开始 快动起来
Now, go on! Vamoose!
赶快 有很多活要干呢
Avanti! There's work to do.
埃尔顿 继续深入
And, Elton, keep infiltrating.
你要不惜一切地获取信息 孩子 明白吗
You will do anything to get that information, boy, anything.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
布里吉…
Oh... Oh, Bridget.
布里吉 可以和你单独谈谈吗
Bridget? Oh, yes. Could I have a word with you in private, please?
斯金纳先生要载我一乘
Mr Skinner's giving me a lift.
我可以送你回去 斯金纳先生不会介意的
Oh, I can drop you at the station. I'm sure Mr Skinner won't mind, will you?
当然不
Not at all.
布里吉 下周见
All right, Bridget, I'll see you next week.
好的
All right, then.
再见
Bye-bye.
斯金纳先生 我不是八卦
Now, Mr Skinner, I don't mean to pry,
但你有没有回吻了布里吉
but did you give Bridget a little kiss back there?
我想是的
I think I did.
如果你方法得当
And if you get your way,
也许你们之间会有更多吻的
might there be more little kisses between the two of you?
我想也许会
I think there might.
我敢肯定  - 真棒
I knew it! That's brilliant.
现在别激动的太早 慢慢来
Now, let's not get excited. We'll see.
潜伏工作进行地很好
Infiltration went well
因为杰琪老是打电话过来 需要这需要那
'cause Jackie kept phoning up, needing this and needing that.
真奇怪 她需要做的事怎么这么多
It was strange, the amount of things that needed doing.
就像她公寓被诅咒了一样
It's like that flat was jinxed.
真奇怪 这些保险丝老是烧断
It's weird, these fuses, they keep on blowing.
附近一定有个变电站
You must be near a substation
因为你总遇到电力高峰
'cause then you get the power surges.
可以了 修好了
Still, there we go. Fixed!
来 给我最喜欢的助手一点小奖励
Here we are. A little reward for my favourite handyman.
我真的不能这样 外面有车在等着我呢
I shouldn't really, I've got the car outside.
你可以随时打出租车啊
You could always splash out on a taxi,
或者…别的
or whatever.
看看会有什么结果
See what happens.
好吧
Right.
干杯
Cheers.
Cheers!
味道很好
Very nice.
这是什么 法国的
What's that, French?
应该是 那些法国人真懂得做这些
I suppose so. They know how to do things, the French.
是洛斯给你的吗 我是说 她在法国吗
Is it from Rose? I mean, is she in France?
我女儿今晚不会回来 以防你想知道的话
My daughter won't be coming back tonight, just in case you're wondering.
这里完全属于我们
We've got the place to ourselves.
好的
Right.
音乐很好听
Nice music.
"美声男伶"组合
Il Divo.
对
Yeah.
你刚刚说
You were saying...
电力高峰
Power surges.
变电站造成的 没错
From the substation, yeah.
它也把这里变热了吗
Is that why it gets so hot in here?
很热吗
Is it hot?
我想是的 你应该把夹克脱掉
Oh, I think so. You should take your jacket off.
不 我很好
No, I'm fine.
看看你 都要沸腾了
No, look, you must be boiling.
哦 你的衬衫
Oh, look at your shirt!
被我弄脏了
I've ruined it.
不 说真的 还好
No, honestly, it's fine.
把它脱掉 我把它拿去洗了
Take it off, I'll put it in the wash.
没关系 只是一小滴
Oh, come on, it's only a little drop.
现在呢
There now.
全毁了
Ruined.
然后我就到了
And there I was,
终极第五步
the ultimate step five.
最完美地渗透
The perfect infiltration.
目标 杰琪·泰勒
Target, Jackie Tyler. Atta boy!
你是对的 确实有点热
You're right, it is a bit hot,
而且越来越热
but it's about to get hotter.
一会见
I'll see you soon.
好的 小心点 再见
All right, be careful. Bye.
你还好吧
Everything all right?
是我女儿
That was my daughter.
看看你 对不起
Oh, look at you. I'm sorry.
我只是有点犯傻
I was just being stupid.
她还好吗
Is she okay?
她离我很远
She's so far away.
有时我被遗弃在这…
I get left here sometimes
不知道她去哪了
and I don't know where she is.
任何事都有可能在她身上发生 任何事
Anything could be happening to her, anything.
我只是有点神经错乱
And I just go a bit mad.
穿上你的衬衫
Oh, put your shirt back on.
她在哪
Where is she?
不重要
Doesn't matter.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你最好走吧
You better go.
其实…
Actually...
那时我突然想到
And that's when it struck me.
脱衬衫时总会想些奇奇怪怪的事
Funny the things you think of with your shirt off.
但那时 我意识到了什么才是真正重要的
But that's when I realised what was really important.
别再管洛斯了
Never mind about Rose.
我甚至不会去问
I'm not even gonna ask.
我会把衣服穿上
And I will put my shirt back on
因为我要出去给我们买个批萨
because I'm gonna go out and get us both a pizza.
因为我想你需要高兴一下
'Cause I reckon you need cheering up.
她出去漂游了 谁留下来来照顾你
She goes swanning off and who's left to care about you, eh?
我说不如点一份美味的批萨
So I say, nice bit of pizza.
我们把电视打开到很大声
We'll put the telly on nice and loud,
把隔壁的女人吵到不得安宁
we'll annoy that woman next door,
就我们两个 最佳搭档 好吗
just you and me, as proper mates. Yeah?
伙伴 来吧
Mates. Go on,
答应吧
say yes.
好
Yes.
突然之间 很多事情变的有意义
All of a sudden, a lot of things made sense.
我一直迷失在阴谋和外星人和目标里
I'd got so lost in conspiracies and aliens and targets,
却一直错过眼前的东西
I'd been missing the obvious.
我真的喜欢杰琪
'Cause I did like Jackie,
但我更喜欢另一个人
but I liked someone else even more.
♪ Hey you with the pretty face ♪
♪ Welcome to the human race ♪
♪ A celebration Mr Blue Sky's up there waiting ♪
♪ And today is the day we've waited for ♪
♪ Oh ho-ho ♪
♪ Mr Blue Sky, please tell us why… ♪
好的 我们进去吧
Right. Let's get inside, then.
批萨要冷了
The pizza's getting cold.
我翻了你的大衣
I went in your coat.
我人生第一次想到 "我来付钱"
For once in my life I thought, "I'll pay."
我想 他是个好男人 他不会接受任何东西
I thought, "He's such a nice man, "he won't accept anything
所以我把十元钱塞进他的口袋
so I'll just slip a tenner in his pocket."
看看我发现了什么
And look what I found.
我女儿的照片
A photograph of my daughter.
不不不 不是你想的那样 我能解释
No, no, no. It's not like that. I can explain.
你当然会
I bet you can.
我不是什么不正当的人 我没在追求她
I wasn't being pervy or anything. I wasn't after her.
我在找博士
I was looking for the Doctor.
我知道
Oh, I know that.
我想明白了
I worked that out.
从来都和我无关 是吧
'Cause it's never me, is it?
不 一开始是那样的 但后来我改变心意了
No, but that's how it started, but I changed my mind.
让我跟你说说那些被抛弃的人的故事
Let me tell you something. About those who get left behind.
因为那很艰苦
Because it's hard.
你最后也会变成这样 很艰苦
And that's what you become, hard.
但如果说我学会了什么
But if there's one thing I've learnt,
那就是我永远不会让她失望
it's that I will never let her down
我这辈子都会保护他俩
and I'll protect them both until the end of my life.
所以不论你想要什么 我警告你
So whatever you want, I'm warning you,
休想得逞
back off.
但杰琪 我只是想见见他
But, Jackie, I only wanted to meet him.
我还以为你喜欢我
I thought you liked me.
是的
I do.
赶紧滚开这里
Just get out of here!
我说滚
I said get out!
让我静一静
And leave me alone!
她是对的
She was right.
这真可耻 我们利用了那个女人
It's shameful. We used that woman.
我就知道不能相信你
I knew I couldn't trust you!
你这个冒失鬼
You broke cover.
你这个笨蛋 你败在了第五步
You stupid little man, you failed step five.
我不在乎第五步
I don't care about step five!
自从你出现后一切都变味了 肯尼迪先生
'Cause it's all gone wrong, Mr Kennedy, ever since you turned up.
我们以前来这儿 每周欢聚
We used to come here every week and we'd have a laugh.
我们是朋友
We were friends.
难怪他们不来了
No wonder they stopped coming.
布丽斯再也没来过
I mean, there's no Bliss anymore,
还有布里吉 她再没有再出现过
and even Bridget, she hasn't turned up.
我一直打电话给她 但没有回复
I've been phoning and phoning, there's no reply.
谁能怪她
Who can blame her?
抱歉 维克多
I'm sorry, Victor,
但现在你靠自己吧
but you're on your own,
因为我要退出
'cause I am leaving
你也是 斯金纳先生
and so are you, Mr Skinner.
至于你 厄什拉
And as for you, Ursula,
你要跟我来
you're coming with me.
我们去金蝉饭店 我们去吃中餐
And we're going to the Golden Locust and we're gonna have a Chinese.
这和那有什么关系
What's that got to do with it?
我是说 你和我 在一起
I mean, you and me. Together.
吃个饭
Having a meal.
如果你愿意
If you want.
我非常乐意
Oh, I'd love it.
你们不能走
But you can't leave.
这样你们永远不知道他在哪里
But you can't leave. You'll never know what he was doing,
你永远不会知道许多年前 博士为什么在你家
the Doctor. You'll never know what he was doing in your house all those years ago.
我永远都不想知道
No, I'll never know.
厄什拉
Ursula,
拿上你的东西
get your stuff.
斯金纳先生 你来吗
Mr Skinner, are you coming?
不是去吃中国餐 如果你不介意 只是走走
Not to the Chinese if you don't mind. just sort of walking out.
我当然愿意
I certainly am.
维克多
Victor,
你好运吧
good luck.
再见
Goodbye.
斯金纳先生
Mr Skinner,
请问你可以待一会吗
would you stay for a minute, please?
我们要出去
We're walking out.
我有布里吉的电话
I've got numbers for Bridget.
我有纪录 我有她的旧号码
I've kept records. I've got old numbers.
我们可以找到她 你和我一起
We could track her down together, you and I.
这才像老队伍的精神
That's more like the old team spirit.
你们俩过的愉快
You two have a nice time.
希望你能找到她
I hope you find her.
我会给你发邮件
I'll email you.
再靠近一点点
Just come a little closer.
我想吃对虾
I love prawns.
香酥脆皮鸭 你呢
Crispy aromatic duck. Do you?
我忘拿手机了
Oh, I left my phone.
真的  - 对 不在我口袋里
Really? Yeah. It's not in my pocket.
咱愤然退出的气势都没了是吧
So much for the big exit. Yeah.
来吧 快点
Come on, hurry up.
我不是反悔 我只是落下了我的…电话
I'm not stopping, I just left my...phone.
维克多
Victor?
拿上你的电话然后离开
Take your phone and go.
斯金纳先生在哪
Where's Mr Skinner?
他去厕所了
He's gone to the toilet.
但这里没有厕所
But we haven't got toilets,
我们都只能用拐角处的酒吧里的
we have to use the pub on the corner.
那他就在那里
Well, that's where he is, then.
救命
Help me!
什么声音
What was that?
没什么 没什么
It was nothing. It was nothing!
救命
Help me!
闭嘴
Shut up!
那是斯金纳先生
That's Mr Skinner.
维克多 看看你的手
Victor, look at your hands.
看看我的其他部分
Look at the rest of me.
你们对外星人有所涉猎
You've dabbled with aliens,
现在看看真正的外星人吧
now meet the genuine article.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God!
你是…
You're a
东西
thing.
一个东西
A thing?
这是我的真身
This thing is my true form.
比你们那粗糙 粉红的躯体好多了
Better than that crude pink shape you call a body.
发生什么了 我在哪
What happened? Where am I?
厄什拉 是你吗
Ursula, is that you?
那是斯金纳先生
That's Mr Skinner.
你对他做了什么
What have you done to him?
我吸收了他
I've absorbed him.
科林 是你吗 科林
Colin? Is that you? Colin?
布里吉 亲爱的
Bridget, my love.
哦 天哪 那是布里吉
Oh, my God! That's Bridget.
科林 你在哪
Colin, where are you?
我在这 布里吉 我很好
I'm here, Bridget. It's all right,
我被困住了
I'm close.
你把他们俩都吸收了
You've absorbed them both.
布丽斯呢 她在哪
What about Bliss? Where is she?
什么
What?
我说你们不会想知道的
I said you really don't want to know.
你把他们都吸收了
You've absorbed them.
你是某种…
You're some sort of
吸收兽
absorbathon!
吸收怪
An absorbaling.
吸收人
An Abzorbaloff.
不错 我喜欢
Yes, I like that.
放他们走
Let them go.
我命令你
I'm ordering you.
放了他们
Let those people go.
但他们的味道很好
Oh, but they taste so sweet.
想想博士
Just think about the Doctor.
他尝起来会怎样
Ooh, how will he taste!
那些经历 那些知识
All that experience, all that knowledge.
就算要我吸收杰琪·泰勒 那也值了
And if I've got to absorb Jackie Tyler to get to him, then so be it.
你敢
Don't you dare!
让他们走 我打也要把他们打出来
If I have to beat them out of you!
不不 请别打我
Oh! Oh! No, no, please don't hit me!
看看我 我只是一只迟钝笨拙的野兽
Look at me, I'm such a slow and clumsy beast.
请别打我
Please don't hit me.
那把他们还给我
Well, then. Give them back.
什么 你说像这样
What, you mean like this?
只要碰一下 就这么简单
Just one touch! That's all it takes!
不 不
No!
放开她
Leave her alone!
别碰我
Don't touch me.
埃尔顿 对不起
Oh, Elton. I'm so sorry
你不能碰我
you can't touch me.
厄什拉
Ursula.
确实很有抵抗性
Most likely to fight back indeed.
放开她
Leave her alone!
好极了
Yes!
不 这不公平
No, that's not fair!
她的味道像小鸡
She tastes like chicken.
埃尔顿 你在哪
Elton, where are you?
求你了
Please.
肯尼迪先生 拜托了
Mr Kennedy, please.
我在请求您
I'm asking you.
我在乞求您
I'm begging you,
把她还给我
give her back to me.
不行
I can't.
他们一旦被吸收 这个过程无法逆转
Once they've been absorbed, the process is irreversible.
等一下
Wait a minute.
现在我被吸收了 我可以读到它的思想
Now I've been absorbed, I can read his thoughts.
天哪
Oh, my God! Elton,
你就是下一个 快走
you're next. Get out of here.
你看见他了 他不会让你走的
Now you've seen him, he can't let you go.
快跑
Just run.
快点 别管我 快走
Go on, never mind me. Get out!
她真聪明
Isn't she the clever one?
快跑 埃尔顿
Run, Elton!
跑
Run!
保护好自己 孩子
Save yourself, boy!
拼命跑
Run for your life!
怎么了
Oh, what's the matter?
这么快就放弃了
Have you given up so soon?
还有什么意义
There's no point.
我能去哪
Where would I go?
我想要的一切…
Everything I ever wanted...
都被吸收了
Has been absorbed.
埃尔顿 别这么说
Oh, Elton. Don't say that.
但这是真的
But it's true.
那加入我们 加入我们 小伙子
Then join us.join us, little man.
过来 这里有永恒的平静
Come on. It's everlasting peace.
过来 加入我们
Come on, join us.
和我溶为一体
Dissolve into me.
有人想跟你说句话
Someone wants a word with you.
你伤了我妈妈的心了
You upset my mum.
一大个外星吸收怪在这里
A great big absorbing creature from outer space
你还急着找我算账
and you're having a go at me?
没有人能让我妈妈伤心
No one upsets my mum.
终于
At last.
终极大餐 博士
The greatest feast of all, the Doctor.
有趣
Interesting.
某种吸收矩阵
A sort of absorbatrix...
吸收隆…吸收人…
Absorbaklon... Abzorbaloff...
吸收人 对
Abzorbaloff, yes!
只有我觉得吗 他是不是有点像斯利辛
Is it me or is he a bit Slitheen?
你是不是来自拉克斯科瑞法洛托瑞斯星球
Not from Rexicoricophalvitorius, are you?
不 我才不是那群猪
No. I'm not that swine!
我鄙视他们 我来自他们的姊妹星
I spit on them! I was born on their twin planet.
真的吗 拉克斯科瑞法洛托瑞斯星的姊妹星是什么
Really? What's the twin planet of Rexicoricophalvitorius?
克洛星
Clom. Clom?
克洛星 对 一旦我拿到你的旅行机器 我就大胜而归
Clom. Yes, and I'll return there victorious, once I possess your travelling machine.
那永远不会发生
Well, that's never gonna happen.
会的
Oh, it will.
你会向我投降 博士 否则这个人就得死
You'll surrender yourself to me, Doctor, or this one dies.
知道吗 我读过你很多资料 博士
You see, I've read about you, Doctor.
我研究过你 充满热情
I've studied you. So passionate.
那么讨人喜欢 你不会让无辜的人死
So sweet. You wouldn't let an innocent man die.
除非你投降 否则我就吸收掉他
And I'll absorb him unless you give yourself to me.
讨人喜欢 或许吧
Sweet, maybe.
充满热情 应该是吧 但不要和友好弄混了
Passionate, I suppose. But don't ever mistake that for nice.
你随便吧
Do what you want.
他会死的 博士
He'll die, Doctor.
继续
Go on, then.
吸收
So be it.
提醒你 其他人可能有话要说
Mind you, the others might have something to say.
其他人
Others?
他是对的 博士是对的
He's right! The Doctor's right!
我们不能让它得逞
We can't let him.
斯金纳先生 布里吉 拉
Oh, Mr Skinner. Bridget, pull!
看在上帝的份上 拉
For God's sake, pull!
就算这是我们最后能做的一件事
If it's the last thing we ever do.
布丽斯 我们大家一起
Bliss! All of us, together,
加油 用力拉
come on! Pull!
LINDA 联合起来
LINDA united!
拉…
Pull!
埃尔顿 手杖 弄断它
Elton! The cane, break it!
我的手杖
My cane!
你这个蠢货
You stupid man!
不
No!
我做了什么
What did I do?
手杖创造了一个限制场
The cane created a limitation field.
现在坏了 他停不下来了
Now it's broken, he can't stop.
这个吸收者正在被吸收
The absorber is being absorbed.
被什么吸收
By What?
被地球
By the Earth.
再见 埃尔顿
Bye-bye, Elton.
再见
Bye-bye.
她是谁
Who was she?
厄什拉
That was Ursula.
就这样
And that's it.
差不多是
Almost.
因为博士还有别的要说
Because the Doctor still had more to say.
你不记得了 对吗
You don't remember, do you?
然后他解释了
And then he explained.
那晚 许多年前…
That night, all those years ago.
你的房子里有个影子
There was a shadow in your house.
黑暗中的一个活影子
A living shadow in the darkness.
一片元素之影从"呼啸宅"里逃脱了
An elemental shade that had escaped from the Howling Halls.
我阻止了它 但…
I stopped it, but
我来不及救她
I wasn't in time to save her.
对不起
I'm sorry.
因为那晚我妈妈死了
Because that was the night my mother died.
我们忘记是因为必须忘记
We forget because we must.
所以 你看到了
So, there you go.
这就是我经历的最可怕的事情
Turns out I've had the most terrible things happen,
和最美好的回忆
and the most brilliant things,
而且有时 我也分不清它们的区别
and sometimes, well, I can't tell the difference.
他们都是同一件事 只不过是我
They're all the same thing. They're just me.
你知道吗 斯蒂芬·金说过
You know, Stephen King said once, he said,
拯救和诅咒是一样的
"Salvation and damnation are the same thing."
我从不理解这句话的意思
And I never knew what he meant.
现在我知道了
But I do now.
因为博士可能很伟大 但回过头来想想
'Cause the Doctor might be wonderful, but thinking back,
我有这么特殊的经历
I was having such a special time,
只一点点 我有过这么美好的小社团
just for a bit. I had this nice little gang.
♪ I'll tell you once more,before I get off the floor… ♪
而他们被摧毁了
And they were destroyed.
不是他的错
It's not his fault.
也许这就是碰到博士会发生的事
But maybe that's what happens if you touch the Doctor,
哪怕只有一瞬间
even for a second.
我一直在想洛斯和杰琪
I keep thinking of Rose and Jackie,
她们还要为此付出多少代价
and how much longer before they pay the price.
还是不要那么悲伤了
Oh, now don't get all miserable.
振作起来 埃尔顿 你还有我
Come on, Elton. You've still got me.
是的
Oh, yeah.
博士说他可以用他的魔棒做最后一件事
'Cause the Doctor said he could do one last thing with his magic wand.
如果我可以钻进这个吸收矩阵 分离出最后的受害人…
If I can key into the absorption matrix and separate the last victim.
全部重建太迟了 但是…
It's too late for total reconstruction, but...
埃尔顿 拿个铁锹过来
Elton! Fetch a spade!
尽管那样 在那一切发生之后
Even then, after all that,
博士最后一次拯救了我
the Doctor saved me one last time.
她就在这
Here she is.
可能比这更糟
Could be worse.
至少我不会变老
At least I'll never age.
而且真的很平静 超出你的想象
And it really is quite peaceful. You'd be surprised.
这是一段奇特的关系
It's a relationship of sorts.
我们成功了
But we manage.
我们甚至有了点爱情生活
We've even got a bit of a love life.
我们还是不要深入这话题了
Oh, let's not go into that.
我不管别人怎么想
And I don't care what anyone thinks,
我爱她
I love her.
但重要的是
But the thing is...
我最后还是买了个缩放遥控
There you are, I even bought a remote zoom.
但我要说的是
But what I wanted to say is,
你知道 当你还是个孩子的时候
you know, when you're a kid,
人们告诉你生活只是 长大 工作
they tell you that it's all grow up, get a job,
结婚 买房 生子 就是这样
get married, get a house, have a kid and that's it.
不
No.
真相是 世界比那更不同寻常…
But the truth is, the world is so much stranger than that.
更黑暗…
It's so much darker
更疯狂
and so much madder.
更精彩
And so much better.
第三十届奥林匹克
30th Olympiad.
太好了
That's great!
他们不安全
They're not safe.
他们在花园里
They're in the garden.
把它们弄进去 求你了
Get them in, I'm begging you.
最近六天里 你们有三个孩子被偷了
In the last six days, three of your children have been stolen.
如果我们找到那股能量来源…
We need to find the source of that power.
它们是孩子的图画 现在出去
These? They're kids' pictures. Now get out!
克洛伊有一种力量
Chloe has a power.
她利用它来诱拐孩子
She's using it to snatch the kids.
出去
Get out!
如果生物可以变成图画
If living things can become drawings,
那么也许图画也可以变成生物
then maybe drawings can become living things.